Joshuah Wolper

joshwolper.github.io | joshwolper@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/joshuahwolper/

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I've always been energized by the intersection of art and science. In my PhD, this manifested as a love for developing computational algorithms to simulate material fracture for animation practitioners and engineers alike. More recently, I picked up UE5 and rekindled a passion for designing and implementing gameplay systems. Now, I'm excited to bring the breadth of skills I gained in CG research to your team! I'm a quick learner, and a strong generalist, well-versed in playing many roles in tough projects and communicating with interdisciplinary teammates.

EDUCATION

The University of Pennsylvania

PhD in Computer and Information Science, **GPA:** 3.87/4.0 Dissertation: Material Point Methods for Simulating Material Fracture

Swarthmore College

B.S. in Engineering, **GPA**: 3.88/4.0 B.A. in Computer Science, **GPA**: 3.90/4.0 Philadelphia, PA Aug. 2017 – May. 2021

Advisor: Chenfanfu Jiang

Swarthmore, PA

Aug. 2013 - May 2017

Aug. 2013 - May 2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Researcher, University of Pennsylvania, SEAS

2021-2023

- Wrote templated and parallelized fracture simulation code in C++ and Python for medical research (git private)
- Worked with mechanics and biology experts to translate real-world physics into computational algorithms
- Implemented cutting-edge algorithms from published research
- Collaboratively managed C++ codebase with Git version control
- Noted by my PIs for my science communication skills; routinely discussed and presented challenging topics

Research Assistant, University of Pennsylvania SIG Lab, SEAS

2017-2021

- Published two open-source fracture simulation codebases in C++ and Python: Ziran2019 and Ziran2020
- Presented cutting-edge computer graphics research at two consecutive SIGGRAPHs: AnisoMPM Recording
- Managed multiple high-impact projects requiring efficient communication with interdisciplinary team members
- Synthesized and augmented peer-reviewed computational approaches to develop new ones
- Collaboratively maintained a large, complex simulation codebase in C++ with Git version control
- Visualized large particle data sets with Houdini and generated collision assets with VDB level sets

Relevant Projects

Unreal Engine 5 Project, Self-Taught Project

2022-Present

- Designed authoring tools in UE5 Blueprint for fast content creation with artistic control: Web Content
- Wrote gameplay mechanics involving Splines, Procedural Meshes, and Instanced Static Meshes

Maya Authoring Tool for Physics Animation, University of Pennsylvania CIS660, SEAS Spring 2018

- Wrote C++ implementation of Projective Dynamics for real-time simulation of coplanar & 3D elasticity: Code
- Integrated the solver into a Maya plug-in for authoring elastic deformations directly in the Maya timeline: Video

Unity Soft-Body Physics Sandbox, Swarthmore College, Engineering Senior Thesis

Spring 2017

- Implemented Position Based Dynamics in Unity for a real-time interactive elasticity sandbox: Video
- Implemented multiple constraint types, interaction modes, and 3D geometries

Funded Game Design Project, Swarthmore College, Halpern Engineering Design Fund

Summer 2015

- Self-taught Unity and built a prototype of a 2D puzzle platformer, inspired by LIMBO: Video
- Wrote gameplay algorithms in C# for character control, swinging ropes, climbing ladders, and solving puzzles

Publications [Google Scholar]

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems: Ubuntu, Linux, Windows, MacOS Best Programming Languages: C++ and Python

Programs & Packages: UE5 and Blueprint, Unity, Houdini, tbb, CUDA, LaTeX, Git, GIMP/Photoshop, Keynote